[
  {
    "main category":"1.1",
    "question":"I am not feeling well",
    "answer": "In case of fever, cough or cold, please take the self assesment test in Aarogya Setu app or contact Aapthamitra helpline 1075. Isolate yourself and consult doctor in case of aggreviation of symptoms"
  },
  {
    "main category":"1.2",
    "question":"I have a cold",
    "answer":"In case of fever, cough or cold, please take the self assesment test in Aarogya Setu app or contact Aapthamitra helpline 1075"
  },
  {
    "main category":"1.3",
    "question":"My neighbour got corona",
    "answer":"In case of coming in contact with an infected person, please isolate yourself and rush to nearest test center in case of any symptoms,  Ensure regular check of your SpO2 levels, incase it falls below 94 consult a doctor"
  },
  {
    "main category":"1.4",
    "question":"I am having breathing difficulty",
    "answer":"Consider using a nebulizer. Consult a doctor first. Isolate yourself and incase of worsening of symptoms please get yourself tested near the closest ICMR approved testing centre."
  },
  {
    "main category":"1.5",
    "question":"I have a fever",
    "answer":"In case of fever, cough or cold, please take the self assesment test in Aarogya Setu app or contact Aapthamitra helpline 1075. Isolate yourself and consult doctor in case of aggreviation of symptoms"
  },
  {
    "main category":"1.6",
    "question":"How do I keep myself protected?",
    "answer":"Wear a mask at all times when outdoors. Wash your hands regularly. Prevent touching eye, mouth and nose. Only step out if it is very necessary.  Maintain social distancing. Ensure to download Aarogya Setu app.You should be good :)"
  },
  {
    "main category":"1.7",
    "question":"Which is better, sanitizer or soap?",
    "answer":"Sanitizer with at least 60% alcohol is recommended over regular soap wash. HOWEVER, There are no studies supporting the effectiveness of homemade hand sanitizer blend in killing the new coronavirus on people’s hands. Experts agree that the best method for cleaning hands is washing for at least 20 seconds with soap and water."
  },
  {
    "main category":"2.1",
    "question":"What all are allowed?",
    "answer":"For a complete overview about the unlock regulations in India, please visit https://covidindia.org/current-rules-and-regulations/"

  },
  {
    "main category":"2.2",
    "question":"What is allowed in unlock 5.0",
    "answer":"For a complete overview about the unlock regulations in India, please visit https://covidindia.org/current-rules-and-regulations/"
  },
  {
    "main category":"2.3",
    "question":"What is coronavirus",
    "answer":"Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) is an infectious disease caused by a newly discovered coronavirus.Most people infected with the COVID-19 virus will experience mild to moderate respiratory illness and recover without requiring special treatment.  Older people, and those with underlying medical problems like cardiovascular disease, diabetes, chronic respiratory disease, and cancer are more likely to develop serious illness.The best way to prevent and slow down transmission is to be well informed about the COVID-19 virus, the disease it causes and how it spreads. Protect yourself and others from infection by washing your hands or using an alcohol based rub frequently and not touching your face. The COVID-19 virus spreads primarily through droplets of saliva or discharge from the nose when an infected person coughs or sneezes, so its important that you also practice respiratory etiquette (for example, by coughing into a flexed elbow)"
  },

  {
    "main category":"2.4",
    "question":"Tell me about COVID-19",
    "answer":"Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) is an infectious disease caused by a newly discovered coronavirus.Most people infected with the COVID-19 virus will experience mild to moderate respiratory illness and recover without requiring special treatment.  Older people, and those with underlying medical problems like cardiovascular disease, diabetes, chronic respiratory disease, and cancer are more likely to develop serious illness.The best way to prevent and slow down transmission is to be well informed about the COVID-19 virus, the disease it causes and how it spreads. Protect yourself and others from infection by washing your hands or using an alcohol based rub frequently and not touching your face. The COVID-19 virus spreads primarily through droplets of saliva or discharge from the nose when an infected person coughs or sneezes, so it’s important that you also practice respiratory etiquette (for example, by coughing into a flexed elbow)"
  },

  {
    "main category":"3.1",
    "question":"What are the symptoms of coronavirus?",
    "answer":"Common signs of COVID-19 include fever, cough and other respiratory symptoms. In more severe cases, it can cause pneumonia, severe illness and death in some patients (WHO). Some patients also present with muscle aches, confusion, headache, and there have been a few reports of diarrhea. Given the similarity with flu and other respiratory diseases, differential diagno- sis needs to be supported by laboratory."
  },

  {
    "main category":"3.2",
    "question":"Will wearing masks prevent the spreading of Coronavirus?",
    "answer":"For common people, it is not necessary to wear masks. Only people infected with COVID-19 and healthcare profes- sionals, who are in contact with such in- fected patients, need to use masks. The rest need not wear. If you are travelling to places where the probability of catch- ing the infection is high, say hospitals, you need to wear masks. If you are using public transport system, where you cannot know if somebody will sneeze or cough, you can use a mask."
  },

  {
    "main category":"3.3",
    "question":"Are there any home remedies to treat COVID-19?",
    "answer":"Home remedies and treatment other than allopathy is not proven science. The best thing is precaution only.Can COVID-19 virus be transmitted in areas with hot and humid climates? From the evidence so far, the COVID-19 virus can be transmitted in ALL AREAS, including areas with hot and humid weather. Regardless of climate, adopt protective measures if you live in, or travel to an area reporting COVID-19."
  },

  {
    "main category":"3.4",
    "question":"why is the coronavirus called covid-19?",
    "answer":"On February 11, 2020 the World Health Organization announced an official name for the disease that is causing the 2019 novel coronavirus outbreak, first identified in Wuhan China. The new name of this disease is coronavirus disease 2019, abbreviated as COVID-19. In COVID-19, CO stands for ‘corona,’ ‘VI’ for ‘virus,’ and ‘D’ for disease. Formerly, this disease was referred to as '2019 novel coronavirus' or '2019-nCov'. There are many types of human coronaviruses including some that commonly cause mild upper-respiratory tract illnesses. COVID-19 is a new disease, caused by a novel (or new) coronavirus that has not previously been seen in humans."
  },

  {
    "main category":"3.5",
    "question":"how does the coronavirus spread?",
    "answer":"The virus that causes COVID-19 most commonly spreads between people who are in close contact with one another (within about 6 feet, or 2 arm lengths).  It spreads through respiratory droplets or small particles, such as those in aerosols, produced when an infected person coughs, sneezes, sings, talks, or breathes. These particles can be inhaled into the nose, mouth, airways, and lungs and cause infection. This is thought to be the main way the virus spreads. Droplets can also land on surfaces and objects and be transferred by touch. A person may get COVID-19 by touching the surface or object that has the virus on it and then touching their own mouth, nose, or eyes. Spread from touching surfaces is not thought to be the main way the virus spreads. It is possible that COVID-19 may spread through the droplets and airborne particles that are formed when a person who has COVID-19 coughs, sneezes, sings, talks, or breathes. There is growing evidence that droplets and airborne particles can remain suspended in the air and be breathed in by others, and travel distances beyond 6 feet (for example, during choir practice, in restaurants, or in fitness classes). In general, indoor environments without good ventilation increase this risk. COVID-19 seems to be spreading easily and sustainably in the community (community spread) in many affected geographic areas. Community spread means people have been infected with the virus in an area, including some who are not sure how or where they became infected."
  },

  {
    "main category":"3.6",
    "question":"what is community spread?",
    "answer":"Community spread means people have been infected with the virus in an area, including some who are not sure how or where they became infected. Each health department determines community spread differently based on local conditions. For information on community spread in your area, please visit your health department’s website."
  },

  {
    "main category":"3.7",
    "question":"is it a risk to receive packages?",
    "answer":"There is still a lot that is unknown about COVID-19 and how it spreads. Coronaviruses are thought to be spread most often by respiratory droplets. Although the virus can survive for a short period on some surfaces, it is unlikely to be spread from domestic or international mail, products or packaging. However, it may be possible that people can get COVID-19 by touching a surface or object that has the virus on it and then touching their own mouth, nose, or possibly their eyes, but this is not thought to be the main way the virus spreads."
  },

  {
    "main category":"3.8",
    "question":"Should children wear masks?",
    "answer":"In general, children 2 years and older should wear a mask. However, CDC recognizes that wearing masks may not be possible in every situation or for some people. Appropriate and consistent use of masks may be challenging for some children, such as children with certain disabilities, including cognitive, intellectual, developmental, sensory and behavioral disorders."
  },

  {
    "main category":"3.9",
    "question":"can I allow my child to go out to play?",
    "answer":"The more people your child interacts with, and the longer that interaction, the higher the risk of COVID-19 spread. While your child may spend time with other people when they return to childcare or school settings, reducing the number of people your child interacts with outside people within your household, childcare facility or school can reduce the risk of getting and spreading the virus that causes COVID-19. CDC recommends children 2 years of age and older wear a mask in public settings or when around people who do not live in their household, especially when it is difficult to stay at least 6 feet from others. However, masks should not be a substitute for other preventive measures such as frequent hand washing and staying at least 6 feet away from others."
  },

  {
    "main category":"1.8",
    "question":"Can coronavirus spread from water.",
    "answer":"Although persistence in drinking-water is possible, there is no evidence from surrogate human coronaviruses that they are present in surface or groundwater sources or transmitted through contaminated drinking water."
  },

  {
    "main category":"1.9",
    "question":"What is the cure for coronavirus",
    "answer":"There are 2 main life saving drugs such as Remdesvir and Dextramehasone. A cheap and widely available drug can help save the lives of patients seriously ill with coronavirus."
  },

  {
    "main category":"1.10",
    "question":"When will vaccine release",
    "answer":"To check the vaccine developments all across the globe visit https://www.raps.org/news-and-articles/news-articles/2020/3/covid-19-vaccine-tracker"
  },

  {
    "main category":"1.11",
    "question":"How do i get myself tested",
    "answer":"COVID testing is available at both government and private facilities. However, in case you need to get a test done, make sure the hospital, clinic or laboratory is ICMR certified. To get a full list of ICMR certfied testing centres near you, visit https://www.icmr.gov.in"
  },

  {
    "main category":"1.12",
    "question":"Do I have to home quarantine after travelling",
    "answer":"Please visit this link for state-wise quarantine guidelines https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&rct=j&q=&esrc=s&source=web&cd=&cad=rja&uact=8&ved=2ahUKEwjqgpaEmcHsAhXY4jgGHT-uC84QFjAAegQIAhAC&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.civilaviation.gov.in%2Fsites%2Fdefault%2Ffiles%2FState_wise_quarantine_regulation-converted.pdf&usg=AOvVaw3KVvyexZQ0HbwVilDGGBr9"
  },

  {
    "main category":"1.13",
    "question":"What are the home quarantine guidelines",
    "answer":"Please visit this link for state-wise quarantine guidelines https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&rct=j&q=&esrc=s&source=web&cd=&cad=rja&uact=8&ved=2ahUKEwjqgpaEmcHsAhXY4jgGHT-uC84QFjAAegQIAhAC&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.civilaviation.gov.in%2Fsites%2Fdefault%2Ffiles%2FState_wise_quarantine_regulation-converted.pdf&usg=AOvVaw3KVvyexZQ0HbwVilDGGBr9"
  },

  {
    "main category":"1.14",
    "question":"Are theatres open",
    "answer":"Yes, Theatre's are open, please visit them cautiously"
  },

  {
    "main category":"1.15",
    "question":"Can I get coronavirus from my pets",
    "answer":"Some pets can spread coronavirus. Please visit this link to get information on the same : https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/daily-life-coping/pets.html"
  },

  {
    "main category":"2.5",
    "question":"Will corona spread through air?",
    "answer":"Studies to date suggest that the virus that causes COVID-19 is mainly transmitted through contact with respiratory droplets rather than through the air"
  },

  {
    "main category":"2.6",
    "question":"Can asymptomatic person infect me?",
    "answer":"The main way the disease spreads is through respiratory droplets expelled by someone who is coughing. The risk of catching COVID-19 from someone with no symptoms at all is very low. However, many people with COVID-19 experience only mild symptoms. This is particularly true at the early stages of the disease. It is therefore possible to catch COVID-19 from someone who has, for example, just a mild cough and does not feel ill. WHO is assessing ongoing research on the period of transmission of COVID-19 and will continue to share updated findings."
  },

  {
    "main category":"2.7",
    "question":"Who is at more risk?",
    "answer":"While we are still learning about how COVID-2019 affects people, older persons and persons with pre-existing medical conditions (such as high blood pressure, heart disease, lung disease, cancer or diabetes) appear to develop serious illness more often than others."
  },

  {
    "main category":"2.8",
    "question":"Will antibiotics work?",
    "answer":"No. Antibiotics do not work against viruses, they only work on bacterial infections. COVID-19 is caused by a virus, so antibiotics do not work. Antibiotics should not be used as a means of prevention or treatment of COVID-19. They should only be used as directed by a physician to treat a bacterial infection."
  },

  {
    "main category":"2.9",
    "question":"How long does the infection stay?",
    "answer":"The infection period for the virus will vary from person to person. Mild symptoms in an otherwise healthy individual may resolve over just a few days. Similar to influenza, for an individual with other ongoing health issues, such as a respiratory condition, recovery may take weeks and in severe cases could be potentially fatal."
  },

  {
    "main category":"2.10",
    "question":"How to dispose masks?",
    "answer":"After use, take off the mask; remove the elastic loops from behind the ears while keeping the mask away from your face and clothes, to avoid touching potentially contaminated surfaces of the mask. Discard the mask in a closed bin immediately after use. Perform hand hygiene after touching or discarding the mask – Use alcohol-based hand rub or, if visibly soiled, wash your hands with soap and water."
  },

  {
    "main category":"2.11",
    "question":"How long does it take for symptoms to show?",
    "answer":"The incubation period means the time between catching the virus and beginning to have symptoms of the disease. Most estimates of the incubation period for COVID-19 range from 1-14 days, most commonly around five days. These estimates will be updated as more data become available."
  },

  {
    "main category":"2.12",
    "question":"What about pet?",
    "answer":"Jason Villano, D.V.M., M.S., M.Sc., a veterinary expert at Johns Hopkins, says,  Despite the very few reports worldwide, including here in the United States, of sick and healthy domestic animals, including pets, testing positive for SARS-CoV-2, the official name for the virus that causes COVID-19, there is little evidence at this time that such animals are easily infected with the virus under normal conditions, or could transmit it.  The World Organisation for Animal Health in Paris, and in the U.S., the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), are closely monitoring the situation but do not recommend routine testing of animals. The cases of the tigers in the Bronx Zoo and, more recently, of the two pet cats in New York, should not be cause for public alarm but a reminder that the COVID-19 crisis is actively evolving and that we have yet to learn more about the virus and its effects on both human and animal health.  At this time, experts recommend keeping pets indoors or avoiding socialization of pets with other animals, and maintaining good hygiene when handling or caring for your animals."
  },
  {
    "main category":"2.13",
    "question":"Will package infect me?",
    "answer":"Most probably not. The likelihood of an infected person contaminating commercial goods is low and the risk of catching the virus that causes COVID-19 from a package that has been moved, travelled, and exposed to different conditions and temperature is also low.  HOWEVER, the coronavirus is known to live on the surface of plastic, metal, etc. for 2-4 days. It is better to isolate the package for this period before opening it. If this is not possible, use latex gloves and dispose."
  },

  {
    "main category":"2.14",
    "question":"Can I shop in infected area?",
    "answer":"It’s best not to make unnecessary trips, but if you need to go to a grocery store, it’s important to maintain social and physical distancing as you shop, and to clean your hands often while shopping and as soon as you get home."
  },

  {
    "main category":"2.15",
    "question":"Should I go to gym?",
    "answer":"As the new coronavirus is spreading, be cautious about all possible exposures, including at the gym or fitness center. The virus isn’t spread through perspiration (sweat), but items touched by many people (barbells, etc.) could pose a risk. In order to practice social and physical distancing during the COVID-19 pandemic, it is best to avoid public places at this time."
  },

  {
    "main category":"2.16",
    "question":"Should I cancel travel?",
    "answer":"At this time, social and physical distancing are important to follow, so overall, travel is discouraged. Outbreaks of the new coronavirus and COVID-19, the disease it causes, are occurring in the United States and in countries around the world. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) has updated travel information on a range of destinations.  Travelers should be cautious about cruise ship travel and situations that involve crowded places. You are less likely to catch the new coronavirus on airplanes because of circulation and filtering, but you may be asked about your infection risk when you book a flight. And be aware that you may be prevented from returning from certain sites should they be on lockdown."
  },

  {
    "main category":"2.17",
    "question":"How many people have been infected?",
    "answer":"WHO is closely monitoring the situation and regularly publishes information about the disease. For more go to http://www.who.int/csr/disease/coronavirus_infections/en/"
  }

 ]
